Protect your own.
The 5th Wave is a science fiction, adventure,
action film directed by J Blakeson.
16-year-old Cassie Sullivan tries to survive in a world devastated by the waves of an alien invasion
that has already decimated the population and knocked mankind back to the Stone Age.
Cassiopeia "Cassie" Sullivan, played by Chloë Grace Moretz.
Ben "Zombie" Parish, played by Nick Robinson.
Oliver Sullivan, played by Ron Livingston.
Lisa Sullivan, played by Maggie Siff.
Evan Walker, played by Alex Roe.
Sergeant Reznik, played by Maria Bello.
The 5th Wave is a 2016 American science fiction action film directed by J Blakeson from a screenplay by
Susannah Grant, Akiva Goldsman and Jeff Pinkner, based on Rick Yancey's 2013 novel of the same name.
The film stars Chloë Grace Moretz, Nick Robinson, Ron Livingston, Maggie
Siff, Alex Roe, Maria Bello, Maika Monroe, and Liev Schreiber.
Development began in March 2012, when Columbia Pictures picked up the film rights to the trilogy of
novels, with Graham King's production company GK Films and Tobey Maguire's Material Pictures.
Filming took place in Atlanta, Georgia, from October 2014 to January 2015.
The 5th Wave was released in the United States on
January 22, 2016, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
Despite negative reviews from critics, the film was moderately successful,
grossing $109.9 million worldwide against a $38–54 million budget.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
dystopia, alien, alien invasion, human subjugation.
The tone is thought_provoking.